After we freeze this tight top coat, we will see that other versions can participate in the simulation, but the frozen version is not involved in the simulation and its shape will not change.
The sewing line is still effective.
Then go to the tool bar of 2D and find the rectangular tool. In the window of 2D, click and drag it to about three times the width of the virtual model's waist.
Then use the adjustment panel tool to adjust to the appropriate width as needed. Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical panel.
In the window of 2D, move the panel and press Shift F to open the arrangement point. Arrange these two panels on the two arrangement points of the waist.
After the panel is aligned,
we go to the 2D window and use the line sewing tool.
Click on the two lines in the front to complete the sewing line, and then click on the two lines in the back to complete the sewing line.
After opening the simulation by pressing Ctrl D, we will see that this panel is now on the virtual model.
If the belt is relatively loose, you can adjust it manually.
Then we can activate the panels that were frozen by us before.
Because it is now worn in the belt.
In the case that it is now stable,
we can gradually adjust it.
The tail-swing rate that was previously reduced returns to 100 little by little.
Note that do not return too much in one go.
Otherwise, it may cause instability due to too many adjustments in one go.
Of course, if you choose to make the inner skirt as a whole,
you can finish the whole skirt first and then add the belt outside.
Then we freeze the belt belt part that has been done, and also freeze the top part.
Here we freeze these panels in order to maintain their current shape.
And when the panels are frozen, the software runs faster.
In order to facilitate our manual reference,
how long is the belt to be made later,
we first move the belt to the waist near the waist in the 2D simulation.
Then we make a rectangular panel according to the 2D simulation,
as its shoulder strap.
Note that because the human body is a three-dimensional model,
it is not a flat surface.
So when we draw the shoulder strap,
we have to make a long section.
This way, we have finished the strap on the front of the right side.
Then we copy and paste a panel.
Then press Ctrl D to create a total of four panels.
So now we have two pairs of shoulder straps corresponding to each other.
Then press Shift F to open the arrangement point.
We arrange the front of this bag.
After arranging, go to the property editor.
Arrange the position of the x-axis under the column.
You can adjust the position of the arrangement in the horizontal direction.
We put it closer to the center of the body.
The same goes for the back.
After arranging the appropriate arrangement point,
adjust the position of the x-axis.
Let it be closer to the center of the body.
Then we are going to start sewing.
If it is inconvenient to sew in the 2D window,
we might as well use the sewing tool in the 3D window.
It's the same as sewing in the 2D window.
Click on a section of the line and then click on another section of the line.
Note that the sewing lines do not cross.
Then it's the bottom part.
Here we are going to use free sewing.
Because we are sewing a whole section of the panel
and a small section of the line on a panel,
so we have to use free sewing.
The back is the same.
Then let's take a look at the free sewing in the 3D window.
Click on it.
Double click to complete the selection.
Then click on the belt.
You can also do free sewing.
Then we can simulate by pressing the control button.
After opening the simulation,
we will see that its shoulder strap is a little out of place.
Then we press the control button to pause the simulation.
Then press Ctrl Z to return to the time when the simulation has not started.
First, we press the control button to open the simulation.
After opening the simulation, we will see that
its shoulder strap is OK.
In order to prevent it from slipping,
we press the W key and click on the panel.
You can create a fixed stitch on the panel.
This way, the panel will not slip down.
Then use the edge sewing line tool
to drag the sewing line in the belt here.
This way, the sewing line moves a little inward.
At this time, after we open the simulation,
the shoulder strap is more straight.
Press the W key and click on the fixed stitch.
You can cancel the fixed stitch.
At this time, we will simulate
whether it can be fixed while dragging the shoulder strap.
In order to prevent it from moving,
we can use the tool on the virtual model.
Click on the panel and then click on the virtual model.
In this way, we can sew the point on the panel
and the point on the virtual model together.
After opening the simulation,
if the shoulder strap is a little unnatural here,
we can find the edge sewing tool.
It is also in the previous download menu.
After selecting this edge sewing needle,
we can adjust the edge sewing tool
and adjust the length of the line.
When the length of the line is set to 2 mm,
there will be 2 mm of space between the two points.
In this way, it looks more natural.
Let's look back.
The fixed needle is fixed in 3D space,
and the fake sewing needle virtual model
is connected to the virtual model.
After that, we can select all the panels and activate them.
At this time, if you see that the shoulder strap is a little long,
you can adjust it again in 2D space.
Be careful not to affect the position of the fake sewing needle.
If the panel is longer,
it may look more obvious.
How do we judge that the panel is short?
First of all, we can press Ctrl Z to return to just now,
when we haven't simulated the whole thing.
Then, in the 3D window,
switch to the hardware image
or press the number key Alt 7 directly.
We can see the stretch on the panel.
The blue and green parts show that it is OK now.
But if there is a red part,
it means that this part is tight.
We may need to adjust the length of the shoulder strap
or the width of the belt.
Because some part of the stretch
may be related to it.
It may also be related to the panel that is sewn with it.
We can adjust it all and try it.
Then we can turn off the hardware image.
Then we will adjust the width of the shoulder strap.
When we adjust it,
first of all,
we avoid adjusting it to the side with the seam allowance.
In the process of moving,
don't forget that the front and back pieces
must move side by side at the same time.
In this way,
we can ensure that the width is correct.
Don't forget to press the Shift key.
You can choose more.
Then, because we have adjusted the width of the shoulder strap,
but free sewing,
its sewing line will not be adjusted automatically.
So we have to use the editor sewing line tool
to select the edge of the sewing line on the panel.
Drag this edge to the blue point.
This represents that the two lines of the sewing line are equal.
This blue point is our reference point.
After adjusting,
we can freeze it into some tape
to adjust other parts.